We'll go over some good and bad examples of Boolean expressions used in if statements.
我们将介绍在 if 语句中使用的一些正反面布尔表达式示例
While true is a valid Boolean expression,
虽然 True 是一个有效的布尔表达式
it's not exactly useful as a condition as it always evaluates to true.
但是并非是有用的条件 因为它始终为 true
So the intended code will always get run.
因此缩进的代码将始终运行
Similarly, if false is not a condition you should run either,
同样 也不应该运行 if false 条件
the condition and the if statement would never occur.
该条件和 if 语句将始终不会发生
In this example, is cold or not is cold,
在此示例中
will always evaluate to true.
is_cold 或 not is_cold 将始终为 true
If it is cold, then is cold will be true.
如果很冷 则 is_cold 将为 true
If it is not cold, then not is code will be true.
如果不冷 则 not is_code 将为 true
This has no use as a condition because the indented code will always get run.
这个条件根本没用 因为缩进的代码段将始终运行
This code is valid in Python,
这段代码是有效的 Python 代码
but it is not a Boolean expression,
但它不是布尔表达式
although it reads like one.
虽然读起来像布尔表达式
The reason is that the expression to the right of
因为 or 右侧的表达式不是布尔表达式
or is not a Boolean expression, it's a string.
而是字符串
Later, we'll discuss what happens when you use
稍后 我们将讨论用非布尔型对象
a non-boolean type object in place of Boolean.
代替布尔型对象 会发生什么
It takes a few more characters,
多了几个字符
but this is now unambiguously a Boolean expression.
但现在毫无疑问是布尔表达式
The expressions on both sides of the logical operator or are each checking something.
逻辑运算符 or 两侧的表达式都在检查某个条件
This is a valid condition,
这是有效的条件
but we could express it more briefly and clearly.
但是我们可以表达得更清晰简练
Is cold is a Booolean expression on its own right,
is_cold 本身是布尔表达式
so we can make the code more readable by using the variable itself instead.
因此我们可以使用变量本身 使代码更容易读懂
If you want to check whether a Boolean is false,
如果你想检查布尔值是否为 false
you can use the "not" operator.
可以使用运算符 not
Let's summarize the lessons from these examples.
我们从这些示例中总结一些经验
True and False are both Booleans,
True 和 False 都是布尔值
but it doesn't make sense to use if True or if False.
但是不能使用 if True 或 if False
Logical operators and, or,
逻辑运算符 and or
and not have specific meanings that
和 not 的含义
aren't quite the same as their meanings in plain English.
与字面上的英文含义不太一样
Make sure your Boolean expressions are being evaluated the way you expect them to.
确保布尔表达式按照你期望的方式进行评估
Don't compare a variable that is a Boolean with equals true or equals false.
请勿将布尔变量与 true 或 false 进行比较
This comparison isn't necessary since the variable itself is a Boolean expression.
这么比较没意义 因为变量本身是布尔表达式